* About ADISC

### Search

 Everywhere Threads This forum This thread

Search titles only _Note_

By: 

Search Advanced search…

Menu

* * *

* * *

Install the app

Install

JavaScript is disabled. For a better experience, please enable JavaScript in your browser before proceeding.

You are using an out of date browser. It may not display this or other websites correctly.  
You should upgrade or use an [alternative browser](https://www.google.com/chrome/).

Privacy Policy
==============

* _Thread starter_ Thread starter [Moo](https://www.adisc.org/forum/members/moo.1/)
* _Start date_ Start date [May 26, 2018](https://www.adisc.org/forum/threads/privacy-policy.116261/)

#### [Moo](https://www.adisc.org/forum/members/moo.1/)

##### ADISC Admin

**Staff**

Messages

3,648

* May 26, 2018

****ADISC (**AB/DL/IC Support Community) Privacy Policy**  
  
**Introduction**  

* ADISC is a support community. As such, we take privacy very seriously.
* This page outlines how we gather, use, and otherwise manage information about you.

**What information do you collect?**  
We collect the following categories of information:  

* Information that you send us yourself, such as the account information you enter when joining our community, the content you submit to us for publishing in our community, and any email you send us.
* Standard information that your software gives us automatically when you access our community, such as your language preference, the previous web page you were on, the page you are asking us our website to show you, your IP address, and the date/time. Your web browser automatically provides this standard information to all websites you visit, whenever you request any web page.
* In some cases, we may get information about you from other places on the web. For example, we may use a geo-location service to convert your computer's IP address into a guess at your physical location, for the purposes of pre-filling a 'location' field in a form, detecting fraud, or enforcing our community rules.

**What purpose do you use the information for?**  

* We use it to run, maintain, protect, develop, enforce the rules of, and otherwise improve, ADISC.
* We are a volunteer-run support community, not a business.
* We are _not_ seeking to make money from you, or your data.

**What is your legal basis for storing this information?**  

* We store information on the basis that it is within our legitimate interest to do so.
* Our interest is in providing support, community and discussion forums to AB/DL/IC people, their friends, family, and allies. We couldn't serve this interest, and thus help you, without storing this data.

**What is your data retention policy?**  

* Data is retained until it is deleted, either by you, or by us.
* When we determine that certain data is only useful for a set period of time, we may automatically delete it after that time.

**Can I view/edit/delete data about me?**  

* Most data we hold about you (e.g: your blogs, photos, links on your profile, etc) you can view, edit or delete at any time, via our website.
* You can only edit your posts on our forum for a limited time after you make them. After that time is over, you must contact us if you want them edited/deleted. Deleting posts is a destructive process that damages our community, infringes on our core interest to provide a supportive discussion forum, creates fraud concerns, etc. We will generally edit/delete specific, individual posts of yours that contain personal information, or otherwise cause a problem for you, if you ask us to. We will generally not mass-delete all posts you've ever made.
* We must retain certain data about you (e.g: your date of birth) for, at minimum, as long as you have an account with us. This is necessary for fraud prevention, legal and technical reasons.
* There is also some data (e.g: entries in server log, including your IP address) that we must retain on all visitors, including those without accounts. We must retain this in order to enforce our terms of service, protect ourselves from cyberattacks, and prevent fraud.

**Browser-Specific Privacy**  
  
**Cookies**  

* Like almost every other website, we rely on cookies to enable basic functionality. This includes logging in, remembering your preferences, and generally providing you a high quality online community to participate in.
* We also use cookies for the purpose of generating anonymous statistics about visitors. See the "Google Analytics" section below for information on how that works.
* We do not use cookies for advertising purposes.

**"Do Not Track" Setting**  

* Like most websites, we do not treat people differently based on the "Do Not Track" setting of their browser. DNT was intended to be a signal to ad networks, but we don't use ads or ad networks on ADISC, so it is redundant.
* For further information, see [Wikipedia](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Do_Not_Track) and [AllAboutDNT.com](https://allaboutdnt.com/).

**Third Parties**  

**Data Sharing**  

* We do not rent or sell data about you.
* We do not allow paid advertising, or ad networks, nor do we share your data for advertising purposes.
* We do not allow social networking plug-ins (like Facebook Connect), nor do we share your data with them. We encourage all our members to avoid sharing sensitive information on social networking accounts operated by for-profit, data-driven companies that force you to post under your real name.
* We only share data about you in limited circumstances, such as:
    * The data is public, such as your posts to public forums, or the public information on your profile. Visitors to this site, including Google, can see public data.
    * It is necessary in order to fulfill your wishes/requests. For example, if you are gifting us money, we may have to share limited information about the gift with our payment processor, in order for them to process the gift.
    * It is necessary in order for ADISC's services and infrastructure to work. For example, if, we route our outgoing 'please verify your email address' email through a third party email service, then we will have to share your email address with them for that to work. Another example: If we're using a web analytics platform, we have to share information on page view requests with them in order for that to work.
    * Exceptional circumstances apply. This would include, but is not limited to, situations where doing so is required in order to comply with the law, alert authorities to a suicidal person needing help, report a serious crime, or similarly deal with a vital emergency. This also covers situations where we are defending ourselves, our reputation, or our rights.

**Google Analytics**  

* We use a tool called "Google Analytics" to track anonymized statistics about our visitors, such as what percentage of visitors use Chrome versus Firefox, what percentage use desktop versus mobile devices for browsing, and so on.
* Those anonymized statistics enable us to make sure those popular browsers / screen sizes / pages / etc work well on our site.
* The data sent to Google Analytics is anonymized (e.g: with the anonymize\_ip setting), and automatically deleted 14 months after your last visit to our site.
* For more info about Google Analytics, see [The Google Analytics Privacy Policy](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en).

**Discord**  

* We use [Discord](https://www.discord.com/) for our live chat system.
* Usage of Discord here is optional, and governed by the [Discord Privacy Policy](https://discordapp.com/privacy).

**Misc  
  
Automated Decision-Making**  

* We use an automated leveling system that assigns you a rank in the community based on the quantity and quality of your contributions. Your rank influences what permissions you have in our community.
* For more information, see [leveling up on ADISC](https://www.adisc.org/forum/threads/leveling-up-on-adisc.131782/).

**GDPR Notice **(EU-Only)****  

* This section _only applies to residents of the European Union_.
* The GDPR asserts that EU residents have a long list of rights with regards to data about them, including rights to access it, rectify errors/omissions, restrict/suspend processing of it, complain about it to a supervisory authority, and in some cases get it in a portable format, withdraw consent for processing it, objecting to its processing, objecting to its processing for direct marketing purposes, and so forth. The extent of these rights depends on many factors.
* If you wish to make a request to us under the GDPR, you can, but:
    * You will probably need to show us your government-issued ID (to prove that you live in or are a citizen of Europe), before you can make any request under the GDPR.
    * You will need to clearly state your request, and allow us time to examine the GDPR to determine if it supports that request or not.
    * If we decide to grant the request, processing may take several weeks.
    * We may decide to block you from accessing or participating in our community in future. We're a support community run by volunteers. Our staff doesn't get paid for the work they do here. Members who create disproportionately large amounts of administrative hassle for us (such as by submitting extremely time-consuming GDPR requests, especially invalid ones) are just not worth the trouble to have as members. ADISC is private property, and we are under no obligation to let someone use it if we don't want to.

**Gifts, Donations, Etc**  

* If you gift us money, you also agree to the privacy policy of whichever payment processor you use to send us the money.
* The payment processor may retain a record of it, just as they retain records for all other money transfers on their platform.

**Effective Date**  

* This privacy policy is effective from Mar 31st, 2019.
* The latest clarifying update to this policy was made June 25th, 2024.

**Country**  

* ADISC is based in the USA.
* If you do not live in the USA, then:
    * By using ADISC, you are sending information to the USA.
    * The laws of the USA may be different to those of your home country.
    * The laws of your home country might no longer apply.

**How do I get notified about changes to this policy?**  

* Updates are typically announced in the [News](https://www.adisc.org/forum/forumdisplay.php?f=2) forum.

**How do I contact you for privacy questions?**  

* Please use the [requests forum](https://www.adisc.org/forum/forumdisplay.php?f=10) to contact us.

Last edited: Jun 25, 2024

* 

Reactions: LostMyShy, Robbie2Rosie, Woncrinklz and 1 other person

Share:

[Discord Integration](https://xenforo.com/community/resources/6058/) © Jason Axelrod of [8WAYRUN](https://8wayrun.com/)

* Cookies
    -------
    
    We use essential [cookies](https://www.adisc.org/forum/help/cookies) to make this site work, and third party cookies for purposes such as web analytics and showing videos in posts.

    * Essential cookies
    
    These cookies are required to enable core functionality such as logging in, security, network management, and accessibility. You may not reject these.
    
    * Optional cookies
    
    In future, we may add enhanced functionality that depends on optional cookies. Accepting or rejecting these cookies determines if that functionality will be available to you, or not.
    
    * Third-party cookies
    
    These cookies are used by third-party service providers we use, such as Google Analytics, a statistical tool that helps us identify problems with, and improve, our website. It is possible we add other services providers (e.g: for performance optimization, statistics, ads, etc) in future.

    Save cookie preferences
